翻译
王小麦
摇滚小子
*你不想嗨起来吗*
*Don't you wanna go down*
翻译
机械章鱼X
吃货丁小七
*你不想嗨起来吗*
*Don't you wanna go down*
翻译
七七
面条打包子
*你不想嗨起来吗*
*Don't you wanna go down*
翻译
小狗子
大家都给我他妈的大声喊出来
Somebody make some motherfucking noise in here!
这帮混蛋
Fuck these people.
这地方太棒了
Man, this place is unbelievable.
这就是顾利拜  伙计
Fucking Goolybib, man.
这帮人不过是开发出了一套破软件
Those guys build a mediocre piece of software,
还不知道能值几个钱
that might be worth something someday,
现在居然能住在这里
and now they live here.
硅谷里美元满天飞
There's money flying all over Silicon Valley
但却一张都没砸到我们头上
but none of it ever seems to hit us.
你吃的是什么
What the hell are you eating?
虾汁  一夸脱卖200美元
Liquid shrimp. It's 200 dollars a quart.
怀利·迪弗雷纳[名厨]做的
Wylie Dufresne made it.
味道如何
How does it taste?
跟我想象中精液的味道差不多
Like how I would imagine cum tastes.
你们感受到了没
You guys taking it all in?
这就是谷歌出价两亿美元
Because this is what it looks like
购买你公司后的样子
when Google acquires your company for over 200 million dollars.
那是达斯汀·莫斯科维茨
Look, Dustin Moskovitz.
[facebook副总裁  马克·扎克伯格在哈佛的室友]
埃隆·马斯克  埃里克·施密特
Elon Musk. Eric Schmidt.
[前者为SpaceX  特斯拉汽车  PayPal创办人
后者为Google执行董事长]
还有那个创办"相簿"的  鬼知道他叫什么
Whatever the fuck the guy's name is who created Photrio.
摇滚小子是这里最穷的
I mean, Kid Rock is the poorest person here.
除了我们以外
Apart from you guys.
这个派对里走动的人
OK, there's 40 billion dollars
身价净值总和有四百亿美元
of net worth, walking around this party.
而你们还在这儿无所事事  喝虾汁
And you guys are standing around drinking shrimp
讨论精液什么味道
and talking about what cum tastes like.
对  我听到了
Yeah, I heard that.
你们这些住我家里的孩子
You guys live in my incubator
需要培养人脉  所以我才带你们来
you've got to network. That's why I brought you here.
是我带你们来的
I got us in here.
那边的贾维德是我的前室友
Javeed over there is my ex-room-mate.
是啊  但是我开的车
Yeah, but I drove.
埃里克·施密特  我是埃利希·巴赫曼
Eric Schmidt, Erlich Bachman.
时间轴
包
这些派对上男女都会像这样分开
It's amazing how the men and women at these things
真是很奇妙
always separate like this.
时间轴
安安
是啊  硅谷的每个派对
Yeah, every party in Silicon Valley
都像是犹太教婚礼
ends up like a Hasidic wedding.
连顾利拜的那些人都没去跟女人搭讪
Not even the Goolybib guys were talking to girls.
他们不需要  大头
They don't have to, Big Head.
这栋房子就足以搭讪了
This house talks to girls.
校对
面条打包子
王小麦
我有七个词送给你们[英文是七个单词]
I got seven words for you.
我爱
I love
顾利拜的
Goolybib's integrated-
多平台功能整合体验
multi-platform-functionality!
说真的
But seriously,
几天前
you know, a few days ago,
我们和贝拉克·奥巴马坐在一起
when we were sitting down with Barak Obama,
我转过身跟他们说
I turned to these guys and said,
"你们知道  我们正大把赚钱
"OK, you know, we're making a lot of money.
确实  我们扰乱了数字媒体业
And yes, we're disrupting digital media.
但是最重要的是
But most importantly
我们正让这世界变得更好
we're making the world a better place.
通过为代码重复使用和代码延展
Through constructing elegant hierarchies
构建完美体系"
for maximum code reuse and extensibility."
大家
So everyone.
敬以后很多和今晚一样的夜晚
Here's to many more nights just like this one.
下面把舞台交给我的好朋友  摇滚小子
Take it away, my good friend, Kid Rock.
真是个混蛋
What a dick.
原创翻译  双语字幕
第
一
季
第
一
集
硅
谷
视效&后期
冰冰爱尖尖
大头  阿斯伯格网上有一个
Big Head, there is a personal ad section
总监
面条打包子
个人广告分类
on this Asperger site.
我擦  有人在找
Holy shit, this one is looking for
"有机会发展到滚床单的
a "Relationship that has the potential to become
恋爱关系"
sexual in nature."
老天  她还真是敢写
Boy, is she on the spectrum.
她都不敢正眼看摄像头
She can't even make eye contact with the camera.
理查德  能和你谈谈么
Richard, can I talk to you for a second?
私下
Solo.
我们得谈谈魔笛手
We need to talk about Pied Piper.
谈什么  网站运转正常
What about it? The website's up and running,
我正在重写代码  现在只缺用户了
I'm just redesigning the compression. It just needs users.
是啊  正是用户
Yeah, no shit.
即使有人想要用它
But even if somebody wanted to use it
他们也搞不明白该怎么用
they wouldn't be able to figure out how to.
那网站太复杂了
It's incomprehensible.
理查德  你向我介绍魔笛手的时候
Now, Richard, when you pitched me Pied Piper
你说它会成为"音乐圈里的谷歌"
you said it was gonna be, "The Google of Music."
这个说辞很不错
which is a really rad way to pitch something.
我真的很喜欢
I mean, I liked it.
我都以为它有能自己的应用呢
I thought it had "Applications".
它都有  听着  等它壮大之后
No, it has all that. Look, when it blows up,
只要它的用户数够多就一定会的
and it will once it reaches a critical mass of users,
到时候魔笛手就能搜索全世界的唱片
Pied Piper will be able to search the whole world
以此查询有没有匹配数据
of recorded music to find out if there's a match to see
来判断你是否侵犯了版权
if you're infringing on any copy righted material.
所以  如果你是写歌的  或者是个乐队
So, if you're a song writer or a band...
首先  没人在乎
OK, first of all, nobody gives a shit
偷别人的音乐  懂吗
about stealing other people's music, OK?
音乐圈里的每个人
Everybody involved in the music industry
要么在偷音乐要么就在被偷
is either stealing it or sharing it.
他们都是一帮傻逼  特别是电台司令
They're all a bunch of assholes, especially Radiohead.
-听着  理查德  -不
- Look, Richard... - No.
是的  他们是傻逼
Yeah, they're assholes.
听着  理查德  如果你想待在这里
Now, look, Richard, if you want to live here,
你必须有所付出
you've got to deliver.
我的培养箱里容不下累赘
I can't have dead weight at my incubator, OK?
或者至少让我看到点希望
Either that, or show some promise for fuck's sake.
像是乳报  大头的程序
Like NipAlert. Big Head's app.
可以告诉你哪里有发情[激凸]的女人
It gives you the location of a woman with erect nipples.
那才是人们想要的
Now, that's something people want.
理查德  你得了解下人性
Richard, you need to get in touch with humanity.
当我把我的公司亚威亚托卖了的时候
When I sold my company, Aviato,
我并不甘心  所以我才创办了这个
I wanted to give back. That's why I started this place,
去做些大事  去改变世界
to do something big. To make a difference.
像史蒂夫一样
You know, like Steve.
乔布斯还是沃兹尼亚克
Uh, Jobs or Wozniak?
均为苹果公司创始人
史蒂夫·乔布斯还是史蒂夫...
Steve Jobs or Steve...
我听到了
Oh, I heard you.
-那是谁...  -乔布斯
- Which one? - Jobs.
乔布斯只会装  代码都不会写
I mean, Jobs was a poser. He didn't even write code.
你最好有多远滚多远
You just disappeared up your own asshole.
-知道吗  快滚  -严格来讲
- You know that? You did. - Well, technically...
大头  我要冥想去了
Big Head, I'm gonna be meditating.
他光知道怎么包装概念
He knew how to package the ideas,
沃兹尼亚克才真的
but it was Wozniak that...
什么是互利  问得好
What is Hooli? Excellent question.
互利并不只是一家普通的高科技公司
Hooli isn't just another high tech company.
互利关心的不只是软件
Hooli isn't just about software.
互利  关心的是人
Hooli. Hooli is about people.
互利一直致力于用原创科技
Hooli is about innovative technology
有所作为
that makes a difference,
改变我们的世界
transforming the world as we know it.
为了创造更美好的人间
Making the world a better place,
我们要实现传输层的最小发包率
through minimal message oriented transport layers.
盖文·贝尔森
互利创始人兼首席创新官
我始终坚信  要想创造奇迹
I firmly believe we can only achieve greatness
必须要先造福人类
if first we achieve goodness.
埃利希要把我扫地出门了
Erlich is gonna kick me out.
但这里的租金我根本付不起
And I can't afford to pay rent here.
简直明抢  一个月两千八
It's insane. $2800 a month,
五个人合租的话也得四千五一个月
$4500 a month... with five people.
天啊  怎么这么贵
Jesus! Why is it so expensive here?
看看这破地方  简直就是棚户区
Look at this place, it's a shithole.
又来一个
Here's another one.
简直是本年度硅谷小姐啊
Miss Palo Alto, 2K14.
老美人儿
There she goes.
互利
老天  营销部那帮人又在开自行车会议
Oh God, the marketing team is having another bike meeting.
一车废物
Douchebags.
这正是盖文·贝尔森教团的日常一天
Yup, another day inside the Gavin Belson cult compound.
你知道彼得·格里高利最近在忙什么吗
Hey, did you hear what Peter Gregory is doing?
你是说他要买太平洋那个小岛吗
You mean buying that island in the Pacific?
不  严格来讲他正自己盖小岛
No, he's building one actually.
真是强人
Baller.
话说回来  他愿意为那些
Anyway, he's also offering a hundred K
从大学辍学实现理想的人
to people willing to skip or drop out of college
赞助几十万美元
to pursue their idea.
我不知道他心里有啥阴影
I don't know what happened to that guy,
但他真是恨死大学了
but he really hates college.
总之他今晚要在帕罗奥多做一次TED演讲
Anyway, he's doing a TED TALKS in Palo Alto tonight.
[非盈利学术研讨会]
-要不要去听听  -我都已经辍学了
- Should we try to get in? - I dropped out of college.
也许我该再考进去然后重新辍学
Maybe I should re-enroll and drop out again.
好从他那里拿钱
Try and get the money.
改变创造机遇
码仔队
Brogrammers.
不好  别过来
Oh, no, no.
给我来杯双重玛奇朵  哥们
Hey, uh, a double macchiato for me, dude.
好
Yeah.
里科  你最近又壮了啊
Hey, Rico, you been working out?
没  我没有
No. No, I have not.
我就算想锻炼也没时间
I don't have time to even if I wanted to.
我光顾着忙我的网站了
I'm too busy working on my website.
我只是不想变成个互利寄生男
Uh, I just, I don't want to end up being a Hooli lifer.
在这工作一辈子
You know, working here forever.
是啊  这不过是世界上最勇于创新的公司
Yeah, working for the most innovative company in the world,
还发最高的工资和股票期权而已
with top pay and vested stock options.
我完全理解你对此鄙夷的心情
I can totally see why you wouldn't want that.
没错  你就是个艺术家  是创业者
Yeah, you're like an artist. An entrepreneur.
突破传统的勇者
An iconoclast.
我不知道  大概吧
I don't know, maybe.
老兄  我们跟你开玩笑呢
Dude, We're just messing with you.
但我们真心想给你的网站帮忙
But we really want to help you with your site.
叫什么来着
What's it called?
魔笛手
Pied Piper.
-好名字啊  哥们  -真是
- Dude, sounds amazing. - Yeah.
不如你发给我们  让我们帮你瞅瞅
Why don't you shoot it over to us and we'll give it a look.
没准能帮上忙呢
Maybe we can help.
-真的吗  -当然
- Uh, really? - Yeah.
那好
OK, yeah.
让别人帮我看看总是好事
I mean it's always good to have more eyes on it.
发给你们了
It's... Sent it.
原来在耍我呢
You're making fun of me.
-怎么会呢  哥们  -你们就是
- Dude, no. - No, you are.
-真没有  里奇  -小里奇  别走啊
- Aw, Ricky, man. - Ricky. Ricky, come back.
其实我叫理查德  所以
It's actually Richard, so that's...
-魔擦手  -魔尿布
- Pied wiper. - Wide diaper.
盖茨  埃里森
Gates, Ellison,
乔布斯  戴尔
Jobs, Dell.
全部中途从大学辍学
All dropped out of college.
硅谷能成为创新的摇篮
Silicon Valley is the cradle of innovation
多亏了这些辍学生
because of drop outs.
大学已经成为了强加在
College... has become a cruel
贫困阶层和中产阶级身上的
expensive joke on the poor
一个昂贵而残忍的笑话
and the middle class
最后获益的却只有大学自己
that benefits only the perpetrators of it.
-那臃肿的管理层  -你这人太危险
- The bloated administrators. - You are a dangerous man,
到处散播你的无知
spewing ignorance!
我不这么看
I don't think so.
我只是在说  人们应该相信自己
I'm just saying people should trust themselves
而不应寄希望于某个
more than a system
只专注于量产负债累累的失业者
that happily churns out unemployed debtors
并宣扬可疑价值观的系统
and provides dubious value.
大学教育的真正价值是难以估量的
The true value of a college education is intangible.
万金油的真正价值也难以估量呢
The true value of snake-oil is intangible as well.
你个法西斯分子
Fascist.
有什么新评论吗
Anything?
推特和图享网上还是老样子
The usual riffs on Twitter and Instagram.
没什么新发现
Nothing I'd fund.
不好意思  请问是格里高利先生吗
Hi, excuse me, Mr. Gregory?
如果你有空的话我想简述一个点子
I have an idea I'd love to pitch you, if you have time.
是我辍学后又回到学校之前想到的
Well, that is before I just give up and go back to college.
不要  不要这么做
Don't! Do not do that.
你可以去汉堡王工作
Go work at Burger King.
或者到森林里去采果子
Go into the woods and forage for nuts and berries.
就是别回学校
Do not go back to college!
我觉得我被涮了
I think I have been played.
好吧  你可以开始讲了
Fine. Go ahead and pitch.
在我系好安全带之前结束
You have until I fasten the seatbelt in my car.
真谢谢你
Thank you so much.
魔笛手是一个用来查找
Pied Piper is a proprietary site that lets you find out
你的音乐是否侵犯他人版权的版权网站
if your music is infringing on any existing copyrights.
想象一下你是个词曲作家
So, imagine you were a song writer, OK?
我不觉得我能写歌
I don't think I could write a song.
假设你是的话
Yeah, no, just imagine if you were.
我甚至不觉得我能说得出
I don't even think I could say,
"魔笛手是个版权网站"这种句子
"Pied Piper is a proprietary site."
好吧我说出来了  但是很拗口
Well, I just did but it wasn't easy.
通过密集计算所有歌曲来寻找配对
Crunching all those songs to find matches
听起来需要非常强大的运算能力
sounds like it would take incredible processing power.
-我的意思是  -没错
- I mean... - Yes.
确实需要
Yes, it does.
不  不  我发明了一个算法
No, no. Its... I made an algorithm.
你不如发个项目链接过来
Look, why don't you send me a link to your project
我们到时看一下
and we'll take a look.
好吧  没问题
OK, yeah, great.
我把算法原型放到Github上了
I put the prototype up on Github.
[全球最大的社交编程及代码托管网站]
魔笛手对吧  我会找来看的
Pied Piper. I'll look it up.
就是那个跟小孩有关的童话
It's like the fable with the kids
后来又出现老鼠啊音乐啊什么的
and then the rats and the music.
这车真窄
That is a narrow car.
操蛋的亿万富翁们
Fucking billionaires.
互利
想看一眼小正太的网站吗
Hey, wanna check out twig-boy's website?
当然
Yes, I do.
你还得自己下载媒体播放器吗
You have to download your own media player?
简直又回到了2009年
Look at me, I traveled back to 2009.
等等
Wait a sec.
文件多大
What is this file size?
1.2兆  不可能
1.2 Megabytes? No way.
音质完全没有受到影响
Wow, that doesn't sound at all downgraded.
文件大小几乎只有一半
The file size is like, half.
而且搜索速度超级快
And look how fast this search is.
老天  怎么能搜得这么快
Holy shit, how did it find a match that fast?
看起来它搜索的是压缩文件
It's like it's searching compressed files?
不可思议
No way.
解压缩完成
测试评分
2.89
快看它的维斯曼评分
Look at that Weissman score.
2.89分
2.89.
你们俩干嘛呢
Hey, Where have you two been?
我们五分钟后就要跟多频路由器队开战了
We're playing the multi-channel router team in five minutes.
他到底是怎么做到的
OK, how the hell did he do this?
而且还是无损压缩
And the compression is totally lossless.
而且他竟然找出了
And he's somehow figured out
能够搜索压缩数据库的方法
a way to do a search on a compressed data space.
-我的天啊  -没错
- Holy shit. - Yeah.
而且我觉得他还没意识到这东西的价值
And I don't think he even realizes what he has here.
他用它做了一个傻逼词曲作家程序
He's using it for some silly songwriter app.
这些家伙都这样  只想着面向消费者
All these guys are like that, they're all about consumer facing.
是啊  但是如果你能把这种东西
Right, but you take something like this,
打造成商务产品供企业使用呢
make it business facing and use it for enterprise?
就能够应用在无数的领域
The applications could be endless.
我记得你是个撒旦崇拜者
Hey, I thought you were a Satanist?
我是个有少许有神论倾向的勒维撒旦教徒
I'm a LaVeyan Satanist with some theistic tendencies.
少许有神论倾向
Oh, some theistic tendencies.
那十字架有什么含意吗
Well then, what's with the cross?
这是个倒十字架
It's an upside down cross.
这个角度看是正十字架
Not from here it isn't.
原来如此  你知道你该怎么做吗
Oh, I see, you know what you should do?
你应该再纹个"此面朝上"
You should get another tattoo that says, "This side up" On it.
波斯语里面这个怎么说
How does this translate into Farsi?
我说的才不是波斯语
That's not the language I speak.
边疆航空可很喜欢我的公司  亚威亚托
Frontier Airlines just happened to like mine, Aviato.
所以我才能有今天的一切
And that's how I got to where I am.
那么  你有什么呢
So... what do you got?
就是这个
OK, here it is.
比特汤
Bit Soup.
[比特  二进制单位]
跟字母汤很像
It's like alphabet soup but
不过里面不是字母而是1和0
it's ones and zeros instead of the letters.
因为这是二进制
'Cause it's binary.
你懂的  二进制只有1和0
You know, binary is just ones and zeroes.
我知道二进制是什么
Yeah, I know what binary is.
老天  我十四岁写机器代码的时候
Jesus Christ! I memorized the hexadecimal times tables
就已经把十六进制表背熟了
when I was 14 writing machine code!
考我九乘以F等于多少  是F15
OK. Ask me what nine times F is. It's fleventyfive.
[他编的  应该是87]
我不需要你来告诉我二进制是什么
I do not need you telling me what binary is,
就像我不需要
just like I don't need you
你满脑子就想着汤  还给它拍照片
thinking about soup or taking pictures of it.
我要你们给我想应用程序  软件和网页
I need you thinking about apps, software, websites.
这里可是硅谷  不是
This is Silicon Valley, all right, not...
德克萨斯州的帕里斯
Paris, Texas.
金宝汤公司[美国著名汤品商]的所在地
That's where Campbell's Soup is.
又是互利打来的
It's the Hooli number again.
肯定是那群码仔队
It's probably those brogrammers.
等不及告诉我我的网站多白痴了
Can't wait to tell me how stupid my website is.
一群混蛋
Assholes.
理查德·亨德里克斯  我就是个傻逼
Hello, Richard Hendricks. I'm a total fucking retard.
你好  我是互利购公司的贾里德·邓恩
Uh. Hi, this is Jared Dunn calling from Hooli.
我代表盖文·贝尔森先生打电话给你
I'm calling a behalf of Gavin Belson.
我没有...你好
I didn't... hi.
盖文先生对你的魔笛手应用十分感兴趣
Gavin is very excited about your Pied Piper application
你是否能到公司来
and we were wondering if you could come in
与我们当面谈谈
for a sit-down with us.
-你现在有空吗  -有
- Are you available now. - OK.
-当然  -好的  我们在这等你
- Sure. Yes. - OK, we'll be here.
再见
Good-bye.
我要去见盖文·贝尔森了
Uh, I have a meeting with Gavin Belson.
他喜欢魔笛手
He likes Pied Piper.
我拥有魔笛手百分之十的股份
I own 10 percent of Pied Piper.
你说它是个糟糕的想法
You said it was a shitty idea.
它曾经是个糟糕的想法
It was a shitty idea.
但我不确定它现在算什么
I'm not sure what it is now.
-什么时候开会  -现在
- What time's the meeting? - Right now.
我得去找件好点的衬衫
I'm gonna need a better shirt.
天呐
Holy shit.
我还在这儿等什么呢  再见
What the fuck am I waiting for? See ya.
就像盖文经常说的那样
Well, it's like Gavin always says,
"改变需要代价"
"It takes change to make change."
好像到处都写满了这句话
Yeah, I think I've seen that written around.
盖文大概要迟到三十分钟
Gavin is running 30 minutes late
但他非常期待见到你  理查德
but you should know he is very excited to see you, Richard.
他和他的精神导师在一起呢
He's with his spiritual advisor.
他不会用那么久的
He shouldn't be that much longer.
我是公司的副总裁
I'm a VP here
但我每月能见到他的时间也就十分钟左右
and I only get to see him about ten minutes a month.
但这十分钟就已让人受益无穷
But that 10 minutes is just incredible.
我听说理查德·亨德里克斯来了
I heard Richard Hendricks was here.
你以前见过盖文吗
Have you ever met Gavin before?
-没有  -没有吗
- No. - No?
我刚告诉过他  真是超凡体验
Oh, I told him, it's amazing.
那种感觉真是无以言表
That hardly begins to describe it.
我发现了一个奇怪的现象
It's weird.
这些程序员  他们总是五人同行
They always travel in groups of five.
其中总有一个高高瘦瘦的白人
These programmers, there's always a tall skinny white guy,
一个瘦瘦小小的亚洲人
short skinny Asian guy,
一个扎马尾的胖子
fat guy with a ponytail,
一个胡子剃成奇怪形状的人
some guy with crazy facial hair
和一个东印度人
and then an East Indian guy.
就好像他们为了得到这种分组
It's like they trade guys
而特意换过人一样
until they all have the right group.
看来你已经深谙人性之道
You clearly have a great understanding of humanity.
然后盖文说  我不是在羞辱你
And Gavin said: I'm not humiliating you,
我是在点拨你
I'm elevating you.
盖文
Ah, Gavin.
我是理查德
This is Richard.
是彼得·格里高利打来的
It's Peter Gregory.
没有
Ah, no.
改变需要代价
坚持就是胜利
失败源于恐惧
快点  大头
Come on, Big Head.
我来了  慢点...
Yeah, I'm coming. Slow...
走那么快干嘛
Why are you going that fast?
因为我们要去见盖文·贝尔森  快走
Cause we've got a meeting with Gavin Belson. Pick up the pace.
-事实上我们没有  -快点
- We honestly don't. - Come on.
事实上我现在正在
I'm actually outside of
盖文·贝尔森办公室外  格里高利先生
Gavin Belson's office right now, Mr. Gregory.
他来了  我能过会儿再...
Uh, here he comes, so can I call you back in...
这位就是理查德·亨德里克斯吧
So, Richard Hendricks is here!
你在这儿呢  理查德
There you are, Richard.
非常抱歉让你等了这么久
So sorry these gentleman have kept you waiting.
-没关系  -事情是这样的
- That's fine. - So here's the thing.
我简直爱死你做的东西了
I love what you did.
-真的吗  -给他讲讲  贾里德
- Really? - Fill him in, Jared.
如你所知  互利大概是
Now, as you know, Hooli is seen as possibly
世界上最先进的公司
the most progressive company in the world.
一半归功于盖文对社会公平的恪守
Part of that is Gavin's commitment to social justice,
但另一半归功于他个人
but part of it is his personal commitment
对互利员工的不懈栽培
to the people that work at Hooli.
怀着同样的心情
In that spirit Gavin is
盖文打算付给你实质的奖金
prepared to give you a very substantial raise...
并提拔你到相应的职位
and a promotion to go with it.
我有百分之十的股份呢
I own 10 percent.
他是住在我家时创建的魔笛手
He created it while living in my incubator.
我是埃利希·巴赫曼  这位是大头
Erlich Bachman. This is Big Head.
我不知道你们在说些什么
I don't know what any of that means,
不过我出六十万美元买你的网站
but I'll give you six hundred thousand dollars for it.
我们有平台和资源来接手你的网站
We have the reach and the resources to take what you have done
并让它红遍全球
and push it to the global level.
你的报价非常慷慨
That is a generous offer.
不好意思  你好
Shit, sorry. Hello.
真的吗  开玩笑吧
Really? No shit, that's...
给你  是彼得·格里高利打来的
Uh, yeah, yeah. No here. It's Peter Gregory.
不知道他是怎么弄到我的号码的
Not sure how he got my number?
你好  我是理查德
Uh, this is Richard.
我可以现在就给你三百万美元
I'll give you three million dollars for it right now!
盖文·贝尔森刚刚
Ah, Gavin Belson just offered
出价三百万美元买我的魔笛手
me three million dollars for Pied Piper.
我打算出价三十万美元
I'm prepared to give you three hundred thousand dollars.
彼得·格里高利出价三...
Peter Gregory just offered me 300, um...
你说的是三十万美元吗
Did you say thousand dollars?
三十万美元买你公司百分之十的股份
For ten percent of your company.
好吧  四百万
OK, four million.
二十万
200 thousand.
-买百分之五  -什么
- For five percent. - Huh?
你刚刚降价了
You just went down.
不  你公司的估价仍为四百万美元
No, you're still valued at four million dollars.
但是这个潜在价值
But you own ninety-five
为数十亿美金的公司95%的股份都归你
percent of a potential billion-dollar company.
不仅如此  我还将帮你打造这个公司
And not just that, I will help you build this company.
我会帮你拓展人脉
I will introduce you to the people you need to know
为你提供咨询
and provide the counsel that you need.
我只会分走很小一部分  公司还是你的
I will take a small piece, but the company will belong to you.
而不是盖文·贝尔森
not Gavin Belson.
你必须明天之前给我答复
You have until tomorrow to decide.
好吧
Ah, OK.
-你知道...  -放聪明点  理查德
- Um, you know... - Pull your head out of your ass, Richard.
我开的价可是四百万美元
I'm offering you four million dollars right now.
我...
I'm....
那不是笔小数目
That is a lot of money.
实际上我得...
You know, I actually have to...
我得去下洗手间
I've got to go to the bathroom.
去尿尿
I've got to pee.
憋死了  膀胱要炸了
It's desperate. I'm bursting.
我马上就回来  但现在
I'll be right back, but right now...
好吧  一千万
OK, 10 million.
不行  也许吧
No. Maybe.
我并没想对你无力
I didn't mean to snap at you.
我们等下再谈
I'll talk... in a bit.
很快回来
Won't be long.
简单介绍下我自己
Little more about me.
我是亚威亚托的创始人
I am the founder of Aviato.
而且我拥有很小一部分'基达'的股份
and I own a very small percentage of Grindr.
这是个男男交友网站
It's a men to men dating site
通过它你可以找到方圆十六公里内
where you can find other men within 10 miles of you,
愿意与你在公厕里做爱的男人
interested in having sexual intercourse in a public restroom.
在同性恋的圈子里  有时会要匿名...
In the homosexual community there's sometimes anonymous...
我知道'基达'是什么
I know what Grindr is.
我也有基友
I have gay friends.
医学中心
你会没事的
So you will survive.
只是很常见的恐慌发作
It's just a garden-variety panic attack.
欢迎来到硅谷
Welcome to Silicon Valley.
像你这种人我们见多了
We see people like you all the time.
-真的吗  -当然
- Really? - Yes.
我得在明天之前做决定
It's just I have to make this decision by tomorrow.
是啊  这里曾经有个病人
Yeah. You know, a while back, we had a guy in here,
和你的状况几乎一样
in almost the exact same situation,
跟别人干或是自己干
"Take the money or keep the company."
发生了什么
What happened?
几个月后
Well, a couple months later
他被送入急诊室  因为试图开枪自杀
he was brought into the ER with a self-inflicted gunshot wound.
看来他真的很懊悔没要那笔钱
I guess he really regretted not taking that money.
他因为没拿钱就崩了自己一枪
He shot himself because he turned down the money?
是啊
Yeah.
不对  他拿了钱
Or no, he took the money.
不对
Or no.
他没拿  我也...
No, he did not. I don't... You know what?
其实我也忘了  不管他选了什么
I don't remember. But whatever it was,
他都悔不当初  然后崩了自己一枪
he regretted it so much that he ended up shooting himself.
-结果现在瞎了  -他瞎了
- And now he's blind. - He's blind?
是啊  顺便说一句
Yeah, just FYI,
如果你想开枪自杀的话
if you're ever gonna shoot yourself,
不要朝着太阳穴开枪
don't hold the gun up to your temple, OK?
那样你的两根视神经
Because that just basically just took out
就都完蛋了  然后
both of his optic nerves and then, you know,
还要再赔上这半边脸
half of his face.
他老婆后来不要他了  因为  你知道
And then his wife left him, because, you know.
-吓死人了  -是啊
- Yikes. - Right.
他可能确实是个编程天才
He may have been a genius programmer
但人体解剖他就不行了
but not so much in human anatomy.
在做决策上也不怎么明智
Or decision making, for that matter.
现在他就得带着张烂脸
Now he's got to live with all that
还有为钱做的糟糕决定度过一生
and whatever terrible decision he made about the money.
如果我又要恐慌发作了该怎么办
Uh. And what do I do if I feel another panic attack coming on.
你有没有兴趣买一个装置
Would you be interested in a device
与你的智能手机相连
that links up to your smartphone
能时刻监控你的体征
and it keeps track of your vitals
它甚至能赶在发生之前探测到
and it tells you, even before it's happening,
你是要恐慌发作  还是心脏病发作
whether you're having a panic attack or an actual heart attack?
听起来不错
Yeah, that sounds great.
你会买的  对吧
You would, right?
很好  这是个好消息
OK, that's great news.
因为现在这个装置还处于试验阶段
Because it's still in prototype phase right now,
我和我的创业伙伴在找投资者
but my start-up partners and I are looking for investors.
比如说现在
Like today.
所以如果你接受了那一千万美元
So will you please let me know...
我把我的电话给你
I'm going to give you my number.
请你一定要通知我
If you do end up taking that 10 million dollars
因为我们可以创建一个更美好的未来
because we could really make the world a better place.
老天
Whoa! Oh, jeez!
理查德
Richard.
我叫莫妮卡  我为彼得·格里高利工作
Hi, Monica. I work with Peter Gregory.
我们在TED论坛场外见过
We met outside the TED...
对  我记得你
Yeah, I remember you.
怎么  你怎么知道我在这
What... How'd you know I was here?
彼得·格里高利正在投资一家公司
Peter Gregory is investing in a company
能利用手机的定位系统来追踪人
that uses GPS in phones to track people.
好恐怖
That's creepy.
你根本不知道有多恐怖
You don't know the half of it.
国会也不知道
And neither does Congress.
你还好吧
Are you OK?
听着  我不想浪费你的时间
Look, I don't want to waste your time.
我准备接受盖文·贝尔森的钱了
I think I gotta take the money from Gavin Belson.
这样当我的眼球被自己打爆时
At least this way when I blow my eyeballs out
还能给我的家人留点钱
I'll have some money left for my family.
老天
Jesus.
抱歉  那个医生可真不怎么样
Sorry. That is a terrible doctor in there.
理查德  在你那个简陋的用户界面之下
Richard, buried in that clunky UI of yours
是一个甩了我们几条街的压缩算法
is a compression algorithm that blew our engineering team away.
你觉得互利准备用它来做什么
And what do you think Hooli is going to do with it?
不知道  这不关我的事
I don't know. That's their business.
这是你一手开发的
This is your baby.
你有没有意识到这么好的算法
Do you even realize the impact that a compression
会对世界产生多大的影响
this good could have on the world?
能瞬间下载文件到你的手机里
Getting any file on your mobile phone in an instant.
给自动驾驶车辆提供导航信息
Navigation data for self-driving cars,
移动设备上传输医学影像
mobile medical imagery,
这些数据都不会在传输时损失其质量
all transmitting with no quality loss.
这将颠覆一切
This is game-changing.
当这一切发生时  你不想成为其主宰者吗
Don't you want to be in the driver's seat when that happens?
你真的想把机会让给互利
You really want to just turn it all over to Hooli
彻底离开这个舞台吗
and walk away?
你说这么多并没有缓解我的压力
Well, you are not making this easier for me.
我也没这个打算
I'm not trying to.
我的意思是你其实让事情变得更糟了
I mean you're actually making it worse.
我现在手麻了  嘴里一股金属味
My hands are tingling. I have this metal taste in my mouth.
我不能再进去了  我要回家了
Actually, I can't go back in there, so I'm going to go home.
-让我送你一程  -很高兴再见到你
- Let me give you a ride home. - Good to see you again.
好吧  谢谢
Uh, OK. Thanks.
老兄  你去哪了
Dude, where have you been?
怎么不接电话
Why won't you answer your phone?
老兄  这已经超出天使名单的范围了
Man, this has grown way beyond AngelList.
[在线创投融资平台]
安德鲁森  上升和其他一堆
Andreesen, Elevation and like a bunch of
种子基金都虎视眈眈
other seed funds are piling onto this thing.
我是说  他们一直在给埃利希打电话
I mean, they've been calling Erlich.
他现在已经失控了
He's out of control.
如果我们拿彼得·格里高利的二十万
What if we took Peter Gregory's 200K
来成立我们自己的公司怎么样
and built our own company?
不好意思  你刚刚说我们
I'm sorry. You said we.
这到底指的是谁
Who's that in reference to exactly?
你  我  迪尼希  大头  我们
You, me, Dinesh, Big Head, us.
我是说  现在魔笛手只是做音频
I mean, right now Pied Piper just does audio,
但我正在想方法压缩图片  视频
but I'm thinking of ways to compress images, video...
我是说  也许彼得·格里高利是对的
I mean, maybe Peter Gregory's right.
也许这能做得很大
Maybe this could be huge.
听着  伙计们  几千年来
Look, guys, for thousands of years
我们这种人一直都被别人踩在脚下
guys like us have gotten the shit kicked out of us.
但现在  第一次  我们生活在一个
But now, for the first time, we are living in an era
我们能主宰和构建帝国的时代
where we can be in charge and build empires.
我们能成为这个时代的维京海盗
We could be the Vikings of our day.
-维京海盗  -你感觉怎么样
- Vikings? - How are you feeling?
你看起来一团糟  老实说
You look super fucked up, to be honest.
谁他妈的又吃了我的藜麦面
Who ate my fucking quinoa again?
所以你真的打算去告诉埃利希
So you're really about to go tell Erlich
他拿不到他的一百万美元了
that he's not going to get his one million dollars?
千万找个我不在的时候告诉他
Yeah, I don't want to be there when you do that.
找个我在的时候
I would like to be there when you do that.
别  就待在这  拜托
No, just stay here, please.
我一直在考虑
Um, so, I've been thinking about
彼得·格里高利  盖文·贝尔森的事
this whole Peter Gregory, Gavin Belson thing.
我想我要选择彼得·格里高利
And, um, I think I'm going to go with Peter Gregory.
-我的意思是  -理查德
- Uh, which I know means... - Richard.
我知道每当你看着我
I know that you look at me,
你看到的是一个对一切都了如指掌的人
and see a guy who has it all figured out.
很大程度上  你是对的  我说真的
And for the most part, you're right, I do.
当我卖掉亚威亚托的时候
When I sold Aviato,
它给了我房子  金钱  好看的衣服
it gave me a house, money, fancy clothes,
所有女人对我的尊重
the universal respect of all the ladies.
但我的心里一直有一个洞
But there's always been a hole in my heart.
不是字面上的洞  像你能
Not a literal hole like you would find
在有先天疾病的孩子身上找到的
in some babies with congenital diseases,
而是一个比喻的洞
but a metaphorical hole.
我觉得那个洞就是"如果"
I guess that hole is the "What if".
如果我没有卖会怎么样
What if I didn't sell?
我永远都不会知道
I'll never know.
所以我现在要和你说的就是
And so I guess what I'm saying to you now is,
你像我一样  理查德
you're like me, Richard.
你想创一番事业
You want to build something
并奋战到底
and see it through.
所以  让我们说清楚
So, just to be clear.
你不介意我拒绝一笔
You're all right with me saying no to a deal
能一下子给你一百万美元净利的生意
that will net you a million dollars outright?
不  理查德  我不是不介意
No, Richard. I'm not all right with it.
我是非常激动
I'm excited about it.
我们一起见证这艘火箭能飞多高  合伙人
Let's see how high this rocket can fly, partner.
好的
OK. Great.
太好了
That's great.
我指得不是合伙人
Not partners, exactly.
但其他都很好
But everything else is great.
你爱叫什么叫什么
Call it what you want.
一直蓝色  一直蓝色  一直蓝色
Always blue, always blue, always blue,
always blue, always blue, always blue,
一直蓝色  一直
always blue, always...
是黄色
Oh! That was a yellow.
多少下  17
What was that, 17?
-相当不错  -伙计们
- Pretty good. - Hey, guys...
伙计们  我能简短地说几句话吗
Guys, can I just kind of say something real quick?
我知道这很蠢但是
I know it's stupid but, um...
我想说
I just want to say, uh,
我希望这家公司和互利
I'd like for this company to be different than Hooli
顾利拜还有其他的都不一样
and Goolybib and all the rest, you know?
我们不要让它变成有骑车开会
Like, let's like not turn this into a corporate cult
把强制性解雇
with bike meetings and voluntary retreats
说成是自愿辞职
that are actually mandatory.
还一直声称要创造更美好的世界的那种公司
And claiming to make the world a better place all the time.
让我们  让我们非同凡想
Let's, uh, let's just think different.
[苹果广告语]
不要非同凡想  那是苹果的
Don't think different. That's Apple.
让我们就  想做就做吧
Let's just... let's just do it.
[耐克广告语]
-那是耐克  老兄  -我知道是耐克
- That's Nike, man. - I know that's Nike.
我擦  我不知道
Fuck it. I don't know.
我们就  让它美梦成真
Let's just make it... Let's just make it happen.
好  同意
Yeah, agreed.
敬他的善行
To his beneficence.
彼得·格里高利
Peter Gregory?
-黑魔王  -当然  黑魔王
- The dark lord. - Of course, the dark lord.
大头
Big Head.
天啊  他真是嗨大了
God, he's worse high.
一直蓝色  一直蓝色
Always blue, always blue,
always blue, always blue...
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为